Register of the Albert Glotzer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Social Democratic Period Papers, 1958-1999
  - Speeches and writings by Albert Glotzer
    - "The Legacy of the Russian Revolution after Eighty Years,", 1997 (Folder 51: 20)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Folder 51: 21)
  - Minutes, 1958-1994
    - 1958 May 30-June 1 (Socialist Party national convention) (Folder 52: 1)
    - 1960 May 28-30 (Socialist Party national convention) (Folder 52: 2)
    - 1961 May-December (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 3)
    - 1962 January-August (Socialist Party, including national convention) (Folder 52: 4)
    - 1963 October-December (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 5)
    - 1964 January-December (Socialist Party, including national convention) (Folder 52: 6)
    - 1965 January-November (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 7)
    - 1966 January-December (Socialist Party, including national convention) (Folder 52: 8)
    - 1967 January-December (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 9)
    - 1968 January-June (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 10)
    - 1969 April-May (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 11)
    - 1970 January-August (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 12)
    - 1971 January-November (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 13)
    - 1972 January-November (Socialist Party) (Folder 52: 14)
    - 1973 January-September (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 1)
    - 1974 March-November (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 2)
    - 1975 January-November (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 3)
    - 1976 January-December (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 4)
    - 1977 January-December (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 5)
    - 1978 January-November (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 6)
    - 1979 January-November (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 7)
    - 1980 January-June (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 8)
    - 1981 June-August (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 9)
    - 1982 August (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 10)
    - 1983 February-June (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 11)
    - 1984 May (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 12)
    - 1986 January-December (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 13)
    - 1987 May-June (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 14)
    - 1989 May-December (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 15)
    - 1990 January-February (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 16)
    - 1991 October (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 17)
    - 1992 January-November (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 18)
    - 1993 February-October (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 19)
    - 1994 February-March (Social Democrats, U.S.A.) (Folder 53: 20)
  - Internal bulletins, 1960-1995
    - 1960 (Folder 53: 21)
      Hammer and Tongs unnumbered issue, Press Bulletin two unnumbered issues, Essays on Politics and Peace in the SP-SDF (all Socialist Party)
    - 1961 (Folder 53: 22)
      Press Bulletin unnumbered issue, Two Views of the Cuban Invasion, Realignment One Year after the Party Convention (all Socialist Party)
    - 1962 (Folder 53: 23)
      Hammer and Tongs no. 1-2 (Socialist Party)
    - 1964 (Folder 53: 24)
      Hammer and Tongs no. 4 (Socialist Party)
    - 1965 (Folder 53: 25)
      Hammer and Tongs no. 1 (Socialist Party)
    - 1974 (Folder 54: 1)
      Notes vol. 3 no. 8/9-11, 11 [sic] (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1975 (Folder 54: 2)
      Notes vol. 4 no. 1-11 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1976 (Folder 54: 3)
      Notes vol. 5 no. 1-12 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1977 (Folder 54: 4)
      Notes vo1. 6 no. 1-12 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1978 (Folder 54: 5)
      Notes vol. 7 no. 1-3, 5-11 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1979 (Folder 54: 6)
      Notes vol. 8 no. 1-2, 4-10, vol. 7 no. 9 [sic] (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1980 (Folder 54: 7)
      Notes vol. 9 no. 1-9, 9 [sic] (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1981 (Folder 54: 8)
      Notes vol. 10 no. 9 [sic], 2-6, 6 [sic], 8-9 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1982 (Folder 54: 9)
      Notes vol. 11 no. 1-6, 8-10, Appeal to Reason no. 3 (all Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1983 (Folder 54: 10)
      Notes vol. 12 no. 1, 3-10, Appeal to Reason no. 6 (all Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1984 (Folder 54: 11)
      Notes vol. 13 no. 1-11 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1985 (Folder 54: 12)
      Notes vol. 14 no. 1-9 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1986 (Folder 54: 13)
      Notes vol. 15 no. 1-2, vol. 17 [sic] no. 3-7, unnumbered issue, 10-11, Hammer and Tongs unnumbered issue (all Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1987 (Folder 54: 14)
      Notes vol. 17 no. 2, 5-6, 10 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1988 (Folder 54: 15)
      Notes vol. 18 no. 1-2, 4-8, 8 [sic], 9, 11 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1989 (Folder 54: 16)
      Notes vol. 19 no. 3-6, 8-11 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1990 (Folder 54: 17)
      Notes vol. 20 no. 1-11, Dialogue unnumbered issue (all Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1991 (Folder 54: 18)
      Notes vol. 21 no. 1, 3-11 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1992 (Folder 55: 1)
      Notes vol. 22 no. 1-10, Dialogue unnumbered issue (all Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1993 (Folder 55: 2)
      Notes vol. 23 no. 1, 3-11 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1994 (Folder 55: 3)
      Notes vol. 24 no. 1-2, 4, 6, 9-10 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
    - 1995 (Folder 55: 4)
      Notes vol. 25 no. 2 (Social Democrats, U.S.A.)
  - Internal documents, 1958-1996, undated
    Includes resolutions, reports, memoranda, discussion papers, circular letters, drafts, convention materials, and financial statements
    - 1958 (Folder 55: 5)
      Includes circulated material on admission of Independent Socialist League members to Socialist Party
    - 1959 (Folder 55: 6)
      Includes report on Socialist Party national conference
    - 1960 (Folder 55: 7)
      Includes Socialist Party resolution on presidential election
    - 1961 (Folder 55: 8)
      Includes draft resolution on John F. Kennedy administration prospects
    - 1962 (Folder 55: 9)
      Includes "Perspectives for the Socialist Party-Social Democratic Federation"
    - 1963 (Folder 55: 10)
      Includes draft resolution on the John F. Kennedy administration by Sam Bottone
    - 1964 (Folder 55: 11)
    - 1965 (Folder 55: 12)
    - 1966 (Folder 55: 13)
      Includes appeal to British Labour Party by David McReynolds re Vietnam War
    - 1967 (Folder 55: 14)
      Includes "A Personal Assessment of Trade Union Prospects" by Brendan Sexton; "As the New Left Views Liberalism" by Steve Max and Douglas Ireland; draft statement on foreign policy by Norman Thomas
    - 1968 (Folder 55: 15)
      Includes statements and draft resolutions on the future of the Socialist Party and on the Vietnam War by Michael Harrington, Norman Thomas, David McReynolds, and Penn Kemble and others
    - 1969 (Folder 55: 16)
    - Undated, circa 1960s (Folder 55: 17)
      Includes "On U.S. Foreign Policy" by Michael Harrington; "The Welfare State and Socialism" by Irving Howe; "Socialist Politics in the Welfare State" by Michael Walzer; "The Crisis in the SP: Departures from Democratic Socialism"; "Toward Political Realignment in America: A Socialist Declaration"
    - 1970 (Folder 55: 18)
      Includes statements of Democratic Socialists for [Barry] Farber
    - 1971 (Folder 55: 19)
      Includes circulated material re prospective unification of Socialist Party and Democratic Socialist Federation
    - 1972 (Folder 55: 20)
      Includes declaration of unity of Socialist Party and Democratic Socialist Federation and draft constitution; article re Democratic Party presidential nomination of George McGovern; material re intraparty disputes with Michael Harrington and with Debs Caucus
    - Undated, circa 1970-1972 (Folder 55: 21)
      Includes "Toward Building a Democratic Left in New York City"; draft international and domestic programs; statements and draft resolutions re Vietnam War
    - 1973 (Folder 56: 1)
      Includes "For the Record: The Report of Social Democrats, U.S.A. on the Resignation of Michael Harrington and His Attempt to Split the American Socialist Movement"; reports on founding of and relations with the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee; statement of Committee for Detente with Freedom; "Realignment and Reaction" by Tom Milstein; resolutions re Israel, Chile, Vietnam, and impeachment of Richard Nixon
    - 1974 (Folder 56: 2)
      Includes constitution of Social Democrats, U.S.A.; resolutions on the economy, energy, detente, and Soviet Jewry
    - 1975 (Folder 56: 3)
      Includes resolution on Vietnam
    - 1976 (Folder 56: 4)
      Includes amended constitution; draft resolutions on the economy, cities, Latin America, and the presidential election
    - 1977 (Folder 56: 5)
      Includes resolutions on Indochinese refugees, human rights, the Jimmy Carter administration, the Middle East, and labor; "A Response to the Miller-Feldman Submission to the Discussion on Economic Policy" by Joseph Ryan
    - 1978 (Folder 56: 6)
      Includes resolutions on foreign policy and economic crisis
    - 1979 (Folder 56: 7)
      Includes draft economic resolution by Joseph Ryan; draft resolution on SALT II
    - Undated, circa 1973-1979 (Folder 56: 8)
      Includes "A Contribution to the Discussion on Economic Policy" by Paul Feldman and Bruce Miller; "A Political and Organizational Overview" by Paul Feldman; draft statement on the international situation by Carl Gershman; draft resolutions on various aspects of foreign and domestic policy
    - 1980 (Folder 56: 9)
      Includes draft resolutions on the status of Puerto Rico, the Soviet Olympics, and the presidential election
    - 1981 (Folder 56: 10)
      Includes draft resolution on foreign policy by Carl Gershman
    - 1982 (Folder 56: 11)
      Includes draft resolutions on El Salvador, South Africa, Southeast Asia, and Reaganomics
    - 1983 (Folder 56: 12)
    - 1984 (Folder 56: 13)
      Includes draft resolutions on the presidential election
    - 1985 (Folder 56: 14)
      Includes "Building a Winning Democratic Coalition" by Penn Kemble; "Remarks on Rebuilding the Democratic Party" by James T. Burnett; resolutions adopted
    - 1986 (Folder 56: 15)
    - 1987 (Folder 56: 16)
      Includes draft policy statement on foreign policy
    - 1988 (Folder 57: 1)
      Includes draft resolution by Charles Cogen "For a Full Scale Evaluation of Socialism and Socialist Parties in the Light of Events" and commentary by Israel Kugler and Emanuel Muravchik
    - 1989 (Folder 57: 2)
      Includes Press Committee report
    - Undated, circa 1980s (Folder 57: 3)
      Includes "Toward Labor's Political Modernization" by Bruce Miller and Paul Feldman; "For a Class Perspective" by Israel Kugler; draft resolutions on assorted foreign and domestic policy issues
    - 1990 (Folder 57: 4)
      Includes "What Does 'Democratic Socialism' or 'Social Democracy' Mean Today?" by Emanuel Muravchik; speeches by William C. Doherty and Jiri Horak; "Social Democracy in Eastern and Central Europe, the Baltics and the USSR"; draft domestic policy statement; draft statement on foreign policy and defense; draft policy for the Persian Gulf
    - 1991 (Folder 57: 5)
      Includes "Memorandum on the SD" by Joseph Ryan; "Unpolished Thoughts on the Good Society and the SD" by Rita Freedman; draft resolutions on drugs and the economy
    - 1992 (Folder 57: 6)
      Includes "The 1992 Elections: An Endorsement for Change"; "Can a Social Democratic Movement Be Rebuilt? The Clinton Victory and the New Moment" by Eric Chenoweth and others; "The Election and Its Aftermath" by David Twersky
    - 1993 (Folder 57: 7)
      Includes statements of resignation by Eric Chenoweth and other officers of Young Social Democrats; "Why America Needs a Social Democratic Movement: A Response to the Challenges of the Post-Cold War World"; "Renewing the Social Contract" by Burnie Bond; "Social Democrats and Trade Unionists Reassess their Relationship at International Workshop" by Dave Peterson and Moira McDaid; "Further Considerations on Party Leadership and the Class" by Mike Jones
    - 1994 (Folder 57: 8)
      Includes "Crime and Violence" by Will Stern; "The Movement Is Everything: Towards Socializing Capitalism" by Hugh Sheehan; draft resolution on former Yugoslavia by Mihajlo Mihajlov; draft resolutions on gun control, crime, and assorted foreign policy and domestic issues
    - 1995 (Folder 57: 9)
      Includes "A Radical Redefinition of Affirmative Action"; "The Two Souls of Affirmative Action: A Social Democratic Perspective"
    - 1996 (Folder 57: 10)
    - Undated, circa 1990s (Folder 57: 11)
  - Public issuances
    - New America, 1963 August, 1968 December 30, 1977 December, 1985 March/April (Folder 58: 1)
    - The Social Democrat, 1973 Spring, 1980 Spring, 1981 Spring, 1982 Summer, 1987 June-July, 1989 Fall, 1990 Winter-Spring, 1991 February-March, 1992 January, September, 1993 Winter (Folder 58: 2)
    - SD Papers (pamphlet series), 1977-1985 (Folder 58: 3)
      Includes Africa, Soviet Imperialism and the Retreat of American Power by Bayard Rustin and Carl Gershman; After the Dominoes Fell by Carl Gershman; The Social Democratic Challenge by Leszek Kolakowski and A Response to Conservatism by Sidney Hook; Selling Them the Rope: Business and the Soviets by Carl Gershman; Rebuilding the Democratic Party: A Matter of Principles by Penn Kemble; The Nicaraguan Democratic Struggle: Our Unfinished Revolution by Alfonso Robelo
    - Leaflets and flyers, 1970-1993, undated (Folder 58: 4)
    - Printed resolutions, statements and issue papers, 1968-1992, undated (Folder 58: 5)
    - Press releases and circulated printed articles, 1970-1987 (Folder 58: 6)
    - Testimonial dinner programs, 1975-1992 (Folder 58: 7)
  - Press coverage, 1970-1986 (Folder 58: 8)
    Printed articles about the Socialist Party and Social Democrats, U.S.A.
  - Local New York issuances and documents, 1969, 1973-1980
    - Minutes, 1969 March-November (Folder 58: 9)
    - Minutes, 1974 May-October and 1975 February-October (Folder 58: 10)
    - Constitution, memoranda, circular letters, and newsletters, 1973-1980 (Folder 58: 11)
  - Youth affiliate issuances and documents
    - Socialist Currents (Young People's Socialist League internal bulletin), 1975 October, 1976 June (Folder 59: 1)
    - Young Socialist Review (Young People's Socialist League internal bulletin), 1959 June, 1961 August 16, 1973 June, 1977 May (Folder 59: 2)
    - Young People's Socialist League pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, and resolutions, 1960-1976 (Folder 59: 3)
      Includes Let Us Live to Make Men Free: The Negro in American Democracy by Tom Kahn; 1961 convention documents; 1966 convention resolutions
    - Young Social Democrats reports, manuals, flyers, and leaflets, 1979-1988 (Folder 59: 4)
      Includes convention speech by Tom Kahn
  - Socialist International issuances and documents
    - Social Democrats, U.S.A. reports re participation in the Socialist International, 1975-1996
      - 1975-1980 (Folder 59: 5)
        Includes report to Socialist International opposing admission of rival American organizations; report of expulsion of Young People's Socialist League from International Union of Socialist Youth; reports by Carl Gershman on Socialist International meetings
      - 1982-1986 (Folder 59: 6)
        Includes reports by Joel Freedman and Rita Freedman on Socialist International meetings; speeches by Joel Freedman and Rita Freedman to Socialist International gatherings
      - 1987-1986 (Folder 59: 7)
        Includes reports by Joel Freedman, Rita Freedman and Douglas Payne on Socialist International meetings, mainly regarding Latin America
      - 1990-1991 (Folder 59: 8)
        Includes reports by Joel Freedman and Rita Freedman on Socialist International meetings, mainly regarding Latin America; speeches by Rita Freedman and Douglas Payne to Socialist International gatherings
      - 1992-1996 (Folder 59: 9)
        Includes reports by Joel Freedman, Rita Freedman, Miriam Muravchik, Douglas Payne and Donald Slaiman on Socialist International meetings, mainly regarding Latin America; speech by Joel Freedman to Socialist International gathering
    - Socialist International internal documents, 1974-1996
      Minutes, transcripts of proceedings, resolutions, reports, bulletins, circular letters, and press releases
      - 1974-1981 (Folder 60: 1)
      - 1982 (Folder 60: 2)
      - 1983 (Folder 60: 3)
        Includes report on meeting of secret regional caucus held in Managua, Nicaragua
      - 1984-1989 (Folder 60: 4)
        Includes resolutions on Panama and other topics; position paper on Eastern Europe
      - 1990 (Folder 60: 5)
        Includes proceedings of Council meeting in New York City; "The Assassination of Lic. Gilda Flores and Dr. Hector Oqueli: An Evaluation of the Investigation and Reports Prepared by the Government of the Republic of Guatemala" by Tom Farer and Robert K. Goldman; "East-West: Common Security" by Eiichi Nagasue; speeches by Willy Brandt, David N. Dinkins, Ulpu Iivari and Lane Kirkland; presentation by Partido Socialdemócrata Cubano; "A Danger-Ridden Tension: An Objective of Peace, Progress and Justice" by Bettino Craxi; resolutions on Persian Gulf and other topics
      - 1991-1995 (Folder 60: 6)
        Includes draft statement on the Middle East; resolutions on assorted topics
      - 1996 (Folder 60: 7)
        Includes proceedings of 20th Congress held in New York City; declarations on security and world economy; assorted draft resolutions; "A Journey to the Heart of the Socialist International, 1992-1996" by Pierre Mauroy
    - Socialist International public issuances, 1972-1974, 1977-1982, 1990
      - Socialist Affairs, 1972-1974, 1977, 1979
        - 1972 February; 1973 September/October-November/December; 1974 January/February-March/April/May; 1977 March/April-September/October; 1979 March/April, November/December, 1972-1974, 1977, 1979 (Folder 60: 8)
        - 1980 no. 1-2, 5-6; 1981 no. 1, 4; 1982 no. 5, 1980-1982 (Folder 61: 1)
        - 1990 no. 2-3 (Folder 61: 2)
      - ICSDW Bulletin (International Council of Social Democratic Women). 1977 no. 2-4; 1978 no. 1, 1977-1978 (Folder 61: 3)
      - Socialist International Women Bulletin. 1979 no. 4; 1980 no. 1-2; undated and unnumbered issue, 1979-1980, undated (Folder 61: 4)
  - Subject file
    Mainly printed matter and circulated documents, with some typescripts and correspondence, arranged by topic or issuing agency
    - A. Philip Randolph Institute. Issuances by and printed articles about the Institute, 1970-1997 (Folder 61: 5)
      Includes The Blacks and the Unions by Bayard Rustin; tributes to and articles about Bayard Rustin, director of the Institute
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Intellectual Freedom. Flyers and statements issued by the Committee, 1972-1974 (Folder 61: 6)
      Includes "The Plight of Soviet Dissidents"
    - Africa. Printed matter, 1964-1992 (Folder 61: 7)
      Includes Ready to Govern: ANC Policy Guidelines for a Democratic South Africa by the African National Congress
    - Americans for Democratic Action. Constitution, resolutions, internal documents, and leaflet, 1960-1974 (Folder 61: 8)
      Includes "What Has Happened to ADA?" by Leon H. Keyserling; statement of resignation by Keyserling
    - Anti-Defamation League. Report on Congressman Paul Findley, 1979 (Folder 61: 9)
    - Asia. Printed matter and circulated documents, 1965-1992 (Folder 61: 10)
      Mainly re Vietnam and China
    - Cannon, James P. Memorial meeting program, 1974; "James P. Cannon in the Workers (Communist) Party, 1922-1928" by the Prometheus Research Library, 1992, 1974, 1992 (Folder 61: 11)
    - Civil liberties. Printed matter and circulated documents, 1968-1979 (Folder 61: 12)
      Mainly issuances of the New York Civil Liberties Union
    - Coalition for a Democratic Majority. Printed matter and circulated documents, 1972-1980 (Folder 61: 13)
      Mainly issued by the Coalition. Includes "For an Adequate Defense" by its Foreign Policy Task Force
    - Committee for Detente with Freedom. Press releases and statements by the Committee, 1973 (Folder 62: 1)
    - Committee for the Free World. Printed issuances, 1981-1990 (Folder 62: 2)
      Mainly issues of the Committee's journal Contentions
    - Committee in Support of Solidarity. Press releases, statements, and serial issues, 1981-1985 (Folder 62: 3)
      Includes Bulletin Solidarnosc no. 1 (1981), no. 2-3 (1982); Voice of Solidarity no. 102 (1985); Violations of Human Rights in Poland, 1984-85
    - Committees of Correspondence. Printed matter, 1992-1997 (Folder 62: 4)
      Mainly issuances of the Committees of Correspondence. Includes: CrossRoads no. 17, 20 (1992); Corresponder vol. 1 no. 2, 4 (1992), vol. 5 no. 2 (1996); The New York Mobilizer unnumbered issues (1994-1997); Perspectives for Democracy and Socialism in the '90s (1992); Information Digest report on the Committees of Correspondence
    - Communism--United States, 1974-1994
      - General, 1974-1994 (Folder 62: 5)
        Printed articles and circulated documents
      - Newsletter of the Historians of American Communism, 1982-1987, 1989-1991 (Folder 62: 6)
        Vol. 1 no. 1-2 (1982), vol. 2 no. 1-4 (1983), vol. 3 no. 1-4 (1984), vol. 4 no. 1-4 (1985), vol. 5 no. 1 (1986), vol. 6 no. 2-3 (1987), vol. 8 no. 1, 4 (1989), vol. 9 no. 1 (1990), vol. 10 no. 1 (1991)
    - Conference on the Democratic Left, 1967-1968 (Folder 62: 7)
      Circulated documents
    - Democratic Socialists of America, 1973-1995
      Includes its predecessor organization, the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee
      - General. Printed matter and circulated documents, 1973-1995 (Folder 62: 8)
        Includes issuances of the organization; printed articles by Michael Harrington; material relating to the organization's proposed merger with the New American Movement
      - Publications, 1973, 1979-1980, 1983, 1985 (Folder 63: 1)
        Newsletter of the Democratic Left vol. 1 no. 2-3 (1973); Democratic Left vol. 7 no. 3 (1979), vol. 8 no. 5 (1980); Socialist Forum vol. 1 no. 1 (1979); Socialist Standard vol. 1 no. 2, 4, 6 (1983), vol. 3 no. 1-3 (1985)
    - Europe, 1975-1994 (Folder 63: 2)
      Printed matter and circulated documents. Includes Für Freiheit, Gerechtigkeit und Solidarität: Sozialdemokraten in Deutschland, 1863-1976; "The Polish Blue Collar Worker" by Aleksander Matejko; Helsinki Watch report on Poland; British Democratic Socialist Bulletin articles
    - James, C. L. R., 1980-1991, undated (Folder 63: 3)
      Printed articles about James, 1980-1991; "C. L. R. James and the American Century, 1938-1953" by Kent Worcester, undated
    - Jews--United States, 1965-1989 (Folder 63: 4)
      Printed articles
    - Labor--United States
      - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations issuances
        Press releases, statements, speeches, reports, printed articles, and serial issues
        - 1972-1984 (Folder 63: 5)
          Includes material on 1980 and 1984 presidential elections; issues of AFL-CIO Free Trade Union News
        - 1985-1994 (Folder 63: 6)
          Includes reports of AFL-CIO delegations to Central America; Worker Rights and the Generalized System of Preferences
      - Jewish Labor Committee issuances, 1962-1981 (Folder 63: 7)
        Statements, printed articles, and circulated documents. Includes "The Status of the Jews in the Soviet Union"; material on antisemitism in Poland; Five Who Led
      - United Federation of Teachers issuances, 1972-1997 (Folder 63: 8)
        Printed matter and circulated documents. Includes "Communism: Its Origins and Practice in the Soviet Union" (internal educational document)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960-1996 (Folder 63: 9)